As well as impressive physical attributes, elephants have a rich cultural heritage, passed down through customs and social behaviour which is learned, remembered, and shared within their herds.
除了令人印象深刻的体格特征外，大象还拥有丰富的文化遗产，这些是通过在其群体内学习、记忆和共享的习俗和社会行为传承下来的。
This is possible partly because of their social structure.
这之所以成为可能，部分原因是它们的社会结构。
Elephants live in complex, tightly knit, multigenerational societies, led by older females known as matriarchs.
大象生活在复杂、紧密联系、多代同堂的社会中，由被称为族长的年长雌性领导。
Younger elephants observe and mimic the behaviour of their elders, learning through experience.
年轻的大象观察并模仿年长者的行为，通过经历和体会来学习。
It helps that the herd does almost everything together, from foraging and feeding to raising each others' young.
象群几乎一起做所有事情，从觅食、进食到抚养彼此的幼崽。
These interactions lead to deep long-lasting relationships, which can last for decades.
这些有益的互动导致了深厚而持久的关系，这种关系可以持续数十年。
Possibly because of these bonds, elephants seem to have emotional capacity.
或许是因为这些纽带，大象似乎拥有情感能力。
Just like humans, the creatures have been seen displaying signs of grief.
就像人类一样，这种生物被观察到表现出悲伤的迹象。
When an elephant dies, others in the herd have been observed to repeatedly return to where the individual passed, which is said to be part of a mourning ritual.
当一头大象死去时，人们观察到象群中的其他大象会反复回到那头大象死去的地方，据说这是哀悼仪式的一部分。
They may sniff and touch the carcass and bones and cover the site with leaves and sand.
它们可能会嗅闻和触碰尸体和骨头，并用树叶和沙子覆盖该地点。
Moreover, a 2020 study by researchers Goldenberg and Wittemyer found that "elephants show broad interest in their dead regardless of the strength of former relationships with the dead individual", which may indicate advanced sentience, the scientists say.
此外，研究人员戈尔登贝格和威特迈尔在2020年的一项研究发现，"大象对死去的同类表现出广泛的兴趣，无论生前与死者的关系强弱"，科学家们说，这可能表明它们具有高级的感知能力。
There's a saying found in many languages – 'an elephant never forgets'.
许多语言中都有一句谚语——"大象永不忘记"。
In fact, memory has been essential to the survival of some elephant herds.
事实上，记忆对一些象群的生存至关重要。
A study within Great Kruger National Park found that, during an extreme drought in 2016, elephant groups led by matriarchs who had previously lived through a severe drought, had higher survival rates.
在大克鲁格国家公园内进行的一项研究发现，在2016年的极端干旱期间，由先前经历过严重干旱的族长领导的象群具有更高的存活率。
Researchers concluded that the matriarchs likely remembered where sources of water could be located.
研究人员得出结论，这些族长很可能记得水源可能位于何处。
So, count yourself lucky that you live on the same planet as these immense majestic animals.
所以，为自己与这些巨大而威严的动物生活在同一颗星球上而感到幸运吧。